

# Ataman Engin Yıldız

E-mail: aenginyildiz@gmail.com Phone: +905445588818

Address: Aziziye District Refik Belendir St. Num: 120/5 Y.

Ayrancı, Çankaya / ANKARA

## Objective

Responsible, enthusiastic software engineer expert in mobile application development and interested in learning new technologies. Possesses interpersonal, communication, and negotiation skills and the ability to develop and maintain relationships. A self-motivated, organized, and committed individual with the ability to pay attention to details and increase efficiency and productivity.

## Work experience

ICterra, Ankara

April 2020 — Current

Software Architect / Sr. iOS Application Developer

- \* Managing the mobile application development teams in terms of running Agile methodologies, creating and assigning tasks on Jira, operating the communication between different teams, and providing assistance on building the code structure.
- \* Cooperate with graphic designers to adapt the UI/UX according to mobile design principles.
- \* Cooperate with back-end developers to adapt or create the services for the mobile platforms.
- \* Maintaining the relationship with the external customers until the closure of the project.
- \* Developing and maintaining the applications on the mobile and managing the entire process.
- \* Preparing technical documents and proof of concept for tender offers.
- \* Performing user tests in order to match the requirements and issues of the project.
- \* Processing Apple Store and Test Flight distributions.
- \* Preparing blogs about mobile technologies.

#### Mobilegion, Ankara

October 2018 — January 2020

#### **Business Partner**

- \* Maintaining the relationship with the external customers until the closure of the project.
- \* Cooperate with graphic designers to adapt the UI/UX according to mobile design principles.
- \* Cooperate with back-end developers to adapt or create the services for the mobile platforms.
- \* Developing and maintaining the applications on the iOS platform and managing the entire process.
- \* Building the in-app advertisement system for internal applications using Audience Network and Google Mobile Ads.
- \* Management and statistic analysis of Firebase, Audience Network, and Google Mobile Ads tools.
- \* Giving training or consultancy on the iOS platform for the companies and organizations.
- \* Processing Apple Store and Test Flight distributions.
- \* Post-release statistics tracking.

#### Wiratel LLC, Ankara

December 2017 — October 2018

Sr. iOS Application Developer

- \* Developing VoIP-based virtual phone application on the iOS platform.
- \* Cooperate with graphic designers to adapt the UI/UX according to mobile design principles.
- \* Cooperate with back-end developers to adapt or create the services for the mobile platforms.

Ataman Engin Vildiz

- \* Performing performance and user interface tests.
- \* Processing Apple Store and Test Flight distributions.
- \* Post-release statistics tracking.

#### Hopes Software, Ankara

June 2016 — December 2017

Sr. iOS Application Developer

- \* Developing anime, comic, and humor-based networking applications on the iOS platform.
- \* Cooperate with graphic designers to adapt the UI/UX according to mobile design principles.
- \* Cooperate with back-end developers to adapt or create the services for the mobile platforms.
- \* Building the in-app advertisement system using Audience Network and Google Mobile Ads.
- \* Processing Apple Store and Test Flight distributions.
- \* Post-release statistics tracking.

#### VLMedia, Ankara

January 2014 — June 2016

iOS Application Developer

- \* Developing dating and social network applications on the iOS platform.
- \* Cooperate with graphic designers to adapt the UI/UX according to mobile design principles.
- \* Cooperate with back-end developers to adapt or create the services for the mobile platforms.
- \* Building the in-app advertisement system using Audience Network, Google Mobile Ads, Smaato, and InMobi.
- \* Performing Unit, Performance, and User Interface tests.
- \* Processing Apple Store and Test Flight distributions.
- \* Post-release statistics tracking.

#### Ikol Mobile, Ankara

March 2013 — January 2014

iOS Application Developer

- \* Developing applications mainly for municipalities on the iOS platform.
- \* Building an internal iOS framework to be used for common projects.
- \* Preparing alpha/beta demo versions for the legal customers.
- \* Performing Unit, Performance, and User Interface tests.
- \* Processing Apple Store and Test Flight distributions.

#### Usta Sofware, Ankara

June 2012 — January 2013

iOS Application Developer

- \* Developing mobile applications on the iOS platform.
- \* Processing Apple Store and Test Flight distributions.

## ARgeneer - Augmented Reality Solutions, Cologne

September 2011 — June 2012

Software Developer (Intern)

- \* Developing utility applications on the iOS platform.
- \* Creating Augmented Reality scenarios for iOS and Android platforms.
- \* Processing Apple Store and Test Flight distributions.

### Education

### BS in Sofware Engineering

November 2009 — June 2013

Atilim University

#### Senior Project (September 2012, June 2013)

A video application to provide guidance in order to find an office/classroom located in the Engineering Building of Atilim University. The application was created using the Dijkstra Algorithm and implemented for iPad devices.

Ataman Engin Yıldız 2

## AS in Computer Technology and Programming

Bilkent University

## **Projects**

#### TrueYogi (August 2021, Current)

TrueYogi is a Yoga application that will be initially made available for the App Store towards the end of 2021. The application provides personalized clusters for each user, giving feedback using pose estimation technologies, tracking their mood, and showing the progress they have made so far.

#### Workit (April 2020, Current)

A Slack/MS Teams-like communication application for businesses on both iOS and Android platforms. Messaging, video/audio call, agile board, scheduling a task features available along with company domain usage.

#### Swiss NutriAct (October 2020, April 2021)

NutriAct is a health application specifically developed for people with cancer disease. The application tracks their daily mood, current symptoms, weight, exercises assigned by the doctors, and a help center to provide assistance whenever they need it.

#### DecisionWise (May 2019, December 2019)

DecisionWise serves as a life consultant to guide people towards better decisions around big or small issues in their lives. It may be questions like "Which job is right for me?", or "How can I earn more money given my circumstances?", or "Do I need to stay in this relationship?".

#### WiraBiz Business Phone System (December 2017, October 2018)

VoIP-based virtual phone application. Receive, review and respond to customer requests from mobile phones.

#### **Better Half (September 2015, Present)**

Better Half is a reminder application for couples. Contains readymade message packages for different moods, reminders, and notifications for special days. In addition, Better Half was featured in App Store as well as put under Trending Apps by Apple.

#### Haber Ne Diyor? (February 2018, April 2018)

A news application allowing users to read and comment.

#### Meme Center (June 2016, December 2017)

Meme Center is a humor magazine application to capture any funny moments and turn them into memes. The main features are taking and sharing pictures, photos, and GIFs in order to create memes to share with the community.

#### Waplog (January 2014, June 2016)

Waplog is a social network application to meet new people and has more than 50 million users. Main features are chatting with new people, sharing photos, friends and people nearby profile visits, rating and commenting on photos.

#### Date Way (August 2014, June 2016)

Date Way is a dating application to meet new people and has more than 20 million users. The application lets users searching singles nearby, meeting new people, chatting and sharing photos.

#### W-Match (June 2014, June 2016)

Waplog Match is a Tinder-like application to meet new people around. Simply like or pass on the other people. If both like each other, they will be matched and can chat in the app.

#### Masq (May 2014, September 2014)

Masq is about expressing thoughts, confessions, secrets, and sharing with friends anonymously.

#### Sakarya Ticaret ve Sanayi Odası (December 2013, January 2014)

Ataman Engin Yıldız

Sakarya Chamber of Commerce mobile application. Committee and commission push notifications, associate companies, news, events, reminders, and all the information about the chamber of commerce.

#### Selçuklu (October 2013, December 2013)

e-Municipal services, planned, continuing, or completed projects, social and cultural events are introduced with enriched contents.

#### Konya City Guide (April 2013, September 2013)

Sort places by distance, get information and get directions, search between places, share locations, browse nearly 800 selected quotes from Mathnawi and share them via Twitter, Facebook, and SMS. A smart transportation system, where is my bus, nearest bike stations, pharmacies on duty, city cameras, events, and surveys are presented.

#### Studienkreis (January 2012, June 2012)

An English learning application for 12 - 16 years old German children to develop their skills. Integrated Augmented Reality scenarios to give a brief about the application.

#### **Other Projects**

There are approximately more than 10 projects that I worked on. These projects either are not available in the stores, were not completed, or are small-scale projects. I can provide further information about them upon request.

## Qualifications

Languages: Objective C, Swift, C# (Unity, beginner), Ionic 5 (Angular, beginner)

Tools and Technologies: XCode, Unity, Angular, Visual Studio, Postman, iOS SDK, Cocoa Touch, Cocoa Pods,

Augmented Reality, Git, Firebase, Agile Methodologies (Scrum), Jira, Asana, ASO

Operating Systems: Windows, OS X

## Languages

Turkish: Native

English: Fluent in speaking, reading, and writing

German: Beginner

## **Interests**

Astrophysics, Patreon, YouTube science channels, traveling, music, online gaming, Blizzard beta testing.

## References

Available upon request.

Ataman Engin Yıldız 4